

Varvara Lazarenko

Address Nijmegen, The Netherlands

Telephone +31 6 2662 9839

E-mail varlazoa@gmail.com

Date of birth 29.12.1998 (25 years)

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a recent graduate of the Medical Biology Master program in the specialisation Science, management & Innovation (SMI) at Radboud University. I am inspired by the societal and business aspects of biotech/medical innovations and enthusiastic about using scientific knowledge to create practical, real-world solutions in healthcare. With a strong biomedical foundation and a keen interest in business, I envision a career in business development, product management, health technology assessment (HTA), value assessment, and health economics.

EDUCATION

09/2022 - 08/2024

MSc in Medical Biology - Radboud University, Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ <u>Specialisation</u>: Science, Management and Innovation
- ✓ GPA 7.63/10.00
- ✓ <u>Principal subjects</u>: Future of health, How Health Systems Work, Sustainable Innovation Management, Methods in Societal Research, Reaching the Sustainable Development Goals
- ✓ <u>Projects</u>: «HTA of a Medical Guidance App for International Students in the NL» «A Shared Ownership Model of the Green Corridor, Nijmegen»
 - «A Circular Alternative to Single-Use Cups Within the Dutch Train System»
- ✓ <u>Master thesis</u>: «Potential added value of home telemonitoring technology in elderly care»

09/2016 - 06/2020

BSc in Biology - Lomonosov Moscow State University (MSU), Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Specialisation: Human and Animal Physiology
- ✓ GPA 4.83/5.00
- ✓ <u>Principal subjects</u>: Human and animal physiology, Electrophysiology of excited cells, Neurochemistry, Physiology of central nervous and visceral systems, Physiology of circulation
- ✓ <u>Bachelor thesis</u>: «Role of TASK-1 channels in arterial tone regulation in different organs in rats»

WORK EXPERIENCE

02/2024 - 08/2024

Intern at Digital Transformation of Rehabilitation Care

HAN University of Applied Sciences – Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ Added value research of home telemonitoring in elderly care based on the HTA framework presented onto the Quadruple aim
- ✓ Deployment of surveys and interviewing medical professionals on their home telemonitoring experience/attitude
- ✓ Cost-effectiveness analysis on home telemonitoring in the Netherlands

02/2023 - 08/2023

Intern at Neuronal Networks of Memory

Donders Institute - Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- √ In vivo Ca²⁺ imaging of the retrosplenial cortex in mice during head-fixed virtual social learning
- √ Management of laboratory animals (mice, handling & feeding)
- ✓ Computational analysis of the obtained data (Python, DeepLabCut)

08/2021 - 08/2022

Assistant at the Science department of the Contract Research Organization

LABMGMU, LLC - Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Developing clinical trial design, synopses, protocols, investigator's brochures
- ✓ User interviews (testing the readability of pharmaceuticals' package leaflets)
- ✓ Project management (control of the deadlines; compliance with the sponsor's requirements)
- ✓ Computational analysis of the obtained data (STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism)

10/2020 - 10/2021

Junior Research Assistant at Faculty of Biology

Lomonosov Moscow State University - Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Physiological and molecular biology experiments (wire myography, real-time PCR, western blot)
- √ Management of laboratory animals (Wistar rats)
- ✓ Statistical analysis of the obtained data (STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism)
- ✓ Project management (experiment and research strategy planning)
- ✓ Presentation of the results at two conferences (Oct, 2020; Apr, 2021)

DIGITAL SKILLS

Python (beginner), DeepLabCut, STATISTICA and GraphPad Prism softwares

LANGUAGES

Russian (native), English (fluent – C_{1-2}), German (low intermediate – A_2 - B_1), Dutch (beginner – A_1)

ACADEMIC HONORS AND AWARDS

2022-2024	Awarded Orange Tulip Scholarship for the studies at Radboud University
2020-2021	Awarded MSU Increased State Academic Scholarship for scientific and academic achievements

2021 Second prize-winner in the Lomonosov Universiade on modern problems of biology

VOLUNTEERING ACTIVITY

2023	Organization of the BBB Career Event 2023, Nijmegen
2022-2023	Organization of volleyball tournaments in the international volleyball group at Radboud
2018-2021	Mentoring first-year students at Faculty of Biology, MSU, Moscow

HOBBIES

Volleyball, reading, drawing, guitar playing, traveling

JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

Available upon request

REFERENCES

Available upon request